Erick Patiño Jaimes

MECHATRONIC ENGINEER FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

CONTACT DETAILS

Email: pj erick@hotmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/erick-patiño-ba7a8216a

Mobile: (+52) 55 12 02 69 02 GitHub: https://github.com/EPJHUB

Portfolio: https://portafolio-delta-gray.vercel.app

LANGUAGES

Spanish

English Intermediate-Advanced

SOFT SKILLS

Responsible
Adaptability
Attention to detail
Problem solving

Creative Collaborative Committed

Native

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Mechanical Design:

SolidWorks Fusion 360

Electronic Design:

Altium Eagle

Programing:

MySQL Postgres
Python HTML5
CSS3 JavaScript
React Tailwind
Sequalize Git
Github Express
Node C

ABOUT ME

Energetic and passionate college graduate with a Bachelor of Science in Mechatronics Engineering, self-taught and enthusiastic for learning and enhancing the knowledge and skills I've acquire during my professional career. Creativity and hardworking are skills that defines me as engineer. Aiming to collaborate in areas such as software development, both mechanical and electric design and automation. Excited about using my expertise and tenacity to grow in the industry.

EDUCATION

Digital Systems Technician Instituto Politécnico Nacional CECYT 9 "Juan de Dios Bátiz"

August 2010 – December 2013 **Mexico City, Mexico**

Instituto Politécnico Nacional UPIITA

August 2014 – December 2019

Mexico City, Mexico

B.S. Mechatronics Engineering

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Mechatronics Engineer-Innovatecsi.

August 2021 – Present

CDMX, México

- Design and implementation of devices for care and monitoring of contact sports athletes in order to prevent concussions with the help of microsensors.
- Programming of microcontrollers focused on radio frequencies and the Internet of Things, for the processing and transmission of data through a wireless network.
- Design and implementation of test boards, radio frequency transmitters and receivers, control boards, as well as the management of electronic component libraries to improve workflow and reduce project development time.
- Development of technical documentation (manufacturing and assembly diagrams, user manuals, connection diagrams, etc.) for compliance with Norma Oficial Mexicana NOM-241-SSA1-2021.
- Implementation of communication protocols for embedded systems.
- Design and implementation of Captive Portal (HTML, CSS and Javascript) for IoT devices configuration.

Integration Engineer-Ericsson Telecom S.A. de C.V.

November 2020 - April 2021

- Integration of new technologies (5G and 4G), remotely reconfiguration and updating of networks
- Collaboration and coordination with international teams to perform reconfiguration and integration activities.
- KPI's inspection to ensure compliance with costumer's expectations, as well as the preparation of reports before and after integration and update activities.

CERTIFICATES

- Coursera Google IT Automation with Python
- Project management and other tools for career development
- English B2 CELEX UPIICSA IPN
- Academio Fundamentals HTML, CSS y Javascript

PROJECTS

Graduation Project: Automatic Vertical Orchard HVA

- Design and implementation of control boards (Altium).
- Design and machining of tools for HVA (SolidWorks, Mastercam X5)